

07929297214

ggiles.analytics@gmail.com

github.com/Gilo243

TECHNICAL SKILLS

A highly motivated, versatile and ambitious analytics professional with a passion for data and technology. Nine years of experience within digital analytics, across both implementation and business intelligence roles, have provided me with a solid foundation in architecting solutions to client challenges around data. I have an enthusiasm for continuous self-development and am always looking to expand my skill set through learning new analytical techniques and tools.

Day to day, I currently specialise in the implementation of analytics-focused technology platforms for enterprise-level clients. These technologies include Adobe Experience Platform, Tealium and Google Marketing Suite, among others. I work daily with programming languages such as Python, Javascript and SQL to process data into useable formats.

- Highly experienced in web analytics systems (incl. Adobe Analytics and Google Analytics)
- Advanced knowledge of Tag Management Systems (incl. Adobe Launch, DTM, GTM and Tealium IQ)
- Python (incl. NumPy and Pandas for data analysis)
- Front-end programming languages (incl. JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
- Advanced Excel (incl. Power-Pivot and DAX)
- Data Visualisation (incl. Seaborn & Tableau)
- Experience with Customer Data Platforms (Tealium Audiencestream)

EMPLOYMENT

March 2021 - Present

Discovery Inc Technical Specialist Technical implementation specialist, responsible for the design, configuration and ongoing maintenance of web analytics and martech systems across the Eurosport brand (Web & App).

September 2017 - March 2021

Mezzo Labs Lead Technical Consultant Lead technical expert for Mezzolabs UK, advising clients through the development of best practice analytics deployments, ensuring the full potential of any analytics investment is realised. Clients sit across a range of sectors, including financial services, media, retail and charity.

Acting as a pre-sales engineer for data consulting projects, providing subject matter expertise in all things related to web analytics deployment, from event-driven data layers through to server-side tracking.

Designing and delivering training, webinars and surgeries for clients and prospects and propagating best practice through Mezzolabs. Responsible for researching advances in the analytics and martech world and mentoring junior technical team members.

March 2017 - September 2017

Havas Media Business Analyst - 02 Responsible for producing analyses and deep dives into O2's marketing performance using various methodologies to best answer clients questions. This includes building reporting dashboards in Excel/Tableau and ad-hoc analysis, including time-series & correlational analysis.

Working with bespoke econometrics tool to provide planning recommendations based on econometric modelling. Part of this process involves creating back end data processes that prepare and cleanse data for ingestion quickly and efficiently whilst maintaining a high level of data integrity.

Working closely with the data operations team to develop an automated process using python that can extract, clean and aggregate data from multiple disparate data sources to reconcile advertising spend.

GREGORY GILES

April 2012 - May 2016

IPG Mediabrands London Ad Ops Report Analyst Lead Responsible for the day to day digital reporting across multiple agencies under the Mediabrands umbrella. Clients included some of the world's largest brands, such as Johnson & Bohnson, Microsoft, Xbox, Exxon Mobil and Rockstar Games.

As the leader of a team of 3 analysts, it was my role to oversee the creation and timely delivery of digital campaign insight reports. This entailed working closely with internal clients/media planner buyers to assess campaign KPI's, relay insights and influence necessary actions.

Provide training and support where needed in Microsoft Excel, PowerPivot and other analytical reporting platforms within the digital advertising industry. Created scripts in python to help automate data cleaning processes and speed up the reporting process.

EDUCATION

2007-10

University of Sheffield - BSc Mathematics

Upper Second Class Honours

Modules included:

- Complex Analysis
- Operations Research
- Financial Mathematics
- Combinatorics
- Codes & Cryptography

2005-07

Tunbridge Wells Grammar School for Boys

A-Levels

Maths (A) Physics (B) Psychology (B)

COURSES & QUALIFICATIONS

Springboard Data Science Intensive - Mentored Course

Complete Python - Bootcamp

Adobe Certified Expert: Analytics Business Practitioner

Tealium iQ: Technical User Certification

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

PERSONAL SKILLS

Analytically minded with sharp attention to detail as evidenced through my qualifications and experience.

Comfortable in handling large amounts of data from disparate data sources and extracting valuable insights.

Confident and approachable team player with first-class interpersonal and communication skills as evidenced through employment, team sports and volunteer work, both in the UK and overseas.

Methodical and reliable, I can manage my time effectively working to targets within strict deadlines, a skill honed from working nine years agency side.

REFERENCES

Available on request